Finding Aid for Michigan Environmental Council records, 1925-2012
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Administrative Files
  - 1993-1996
    - Issue files
      - Water
        - Well testing, 1990-1994 (Box 15)
        - Wellhead protection, 1989-1993 (Box 15)
        - Zero discharge, 1989-1991 (Box 15)
      - Wheatfield Township (Deer Creek Golf Course), 1993-1994 (Box 15)
      - Wildlife
        - Endangered species, 1979-1982 (Box 15)
        - Fish, 1996 (Box 15)
        - Miscellaneous, circa 1992-1995 (Box 15)
        - Nongame, 1992 (Box 15)
      - Workplace right to know (Community right to know), 1982-1991 (Box 15)
- Correspondence
  The Correspondence series contains individual and mass-mailings from 1981 through 1999 that were originally collected in binders by MEC in addition to miscellaneous items from 1985-2005. The series is mainly composed of outgoing correspondence (except for the miscellaneous items); recipients include politicians, government officials, corporate figures, charitable foundations, and other environmental groups.
  - 1981 (Box 15)
  - 1982 (Box 15)
  - 1983 (Box 15)
  - 1984 (Box 15)
  - 1985 (Box 15)
  - 1986 (Box 15)
  - 1987 (Box 15)
  - 1988 (Box 15)
  - 1989 (Box 15)
  - 1990 (Box 15)
  - 1991 (Box 15)
  - 1992 (Box 15)
  - 1993 (Box 15)
  - 1994 (Box 15)
  - January 1995 (Box 15)
  - February 1995 (Box 15)
  - March 1-15, 1995 (Box 15)
  - March 16-31, 1995 (Box 15)
  - April 1-14, 1995 (Box 16)
  - April 15-30, 1995 (Box 16)
  - May 1995 (Box 16)
  - June 1995 (Box 16)
  - July 1995 (Box 16)
  - August 1995 (Box 16)
  - September 1995 (Box 16)
  - October 1995 (Box 16)
  - November 1995 (Box 16)
  - December 1995 (Box 16)
  - January 1996 (Box 16)
  - February 1996 (Box 16)
  - March 1996 (Box 16)
  - April 1996 (Box 16)
  - May 1996 (Box 16)
  - June 1996 (Box 17)
  - July 1996 (Box 17)
  - August 1996 (Box 17)
  - September 1996 (Box 17)
  - October 1996 (Box 17)
  - November 1996 (Box 17)
  - December 1996 (Box 17)
  - January 1997 (Box 17)
  - February 1-13, 1997 (Box 17)
  - February 14-28, 1997 (Box 17)
  - March 1997 (Box 17)
  - April 1997 (Box 17)
  - May 1997 (Box 17)
  - June 1997 (Box 17)
  - July 1997 (Box 17)
  - August 1997 (Box 17)
  - September 1997 (Box 17)
  - October 1997 (Box 17)
  - November 1997 (Box 17)
  - December 1997 (Box 17)
  - January 1998 (Box 17)
  - February 1998 (Box 17)
  - March 1998 (Box 17)
  - April 1998 (Box 17)
  - May 1998 (Box 17)
  - June 1998 (Box 17)
  - July 1998 (Box 17)
  - August 1998 (Box 17)
  - September 1998 (Box 17)
  - October 1998 (Box 17)
  - November 1998 (Box 17)
  - December 1998 (Box 17)
  - January 1999 (Box 17)
  - February 1999 (Box 17)
  - March 1999 (Box 17)
  - April 1999 (Box 17)
  - May 1999 (Box 17)
  - June 1999 (Box 17)
  - July 1999 (Box 18)
  - August 1999 (Box 18)
  - September 1999 (Box 18)
  - October 1999 (Box 18)
  - November 1999 (Box 18)
  - December 1999 (Box 18)
  - General, 1985-2005 (Box 18)
- Organizational Records (Policies, Minutes, Reports, etc.)
  The Organizational Records (Policies, Minutes, Reports, etc.) series details the history and operation of MEC from its creation in 1980 through 2008. A wide range of content is included: official policies, bylaws, and organizational history; meeting minutes, agendas, and material relating to the MEC Board of Directors; budgets, grant information, lobbying records, and endowment development; and strategic planning documents, annual reports, annual awards ceremonies.
  - Administrative Policies, 1986-1987 (Box 18)
  - Articles of Incorporation, 1998 (Box 18)
  - Awards
    - Milliken Award
      - Hamp, Steve, 2000 (Box 18)
      - Wege, Peter, 2002 (Box 18)
      - Fluharty, Marty, 2003 (Box 18)
      - Karmonos, Peter, 2004 (Box 18)
      - Dingell, John, 2005 (Box 18)
    - Petosky Prize, 2001-2006 (Box 18)
  - Board of Directors, 1995-2008 (Box 18)
  - Board Meeting Agendas, Minutes, and Supporting Materials, 1996-2007; 3 folders (Box 18)
  - Budgets, 1992-2004; 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Bylaws, 1983-2007 (Box 18)
  - Campaign Guidance for Coalition Initiatives, 2006 (Box 18)
  - Communication Audit and Message Development, 1995-2002 (Box 18)
  - Environmental History Project Celebration, 1999 (Box 18)
  - Finance and Development Committee, 2000-2004; 4 folders (Box 18)
    (includes President's Council materials)
  - Governance
    - Correspondence, 2004-2007; 2 folders (Box 19)
    - Proposals and Strategies, 1994-1995 (Box 19)
  - Grant Budgets, 2002-2006 (Box 19)
  - Grant Tracking, 2003-2008 (Box 19)
  - History, 1980-2005 (Box 19)
  - Lobbying File, 1997-2004; 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Office Procedure Manual, 2006 (Box 19)
  - Official Policy, 1987-1995 (Box 19)
    (material formerly in a binder)
  - Personnel Policy, 1994-2008 (Box 19)
  - President's Performance Review, 1997-1998 (Box 19)
  - Press File, 1994-2001 (Box 19)
  - Reports, 1995-2007 (Box 19)
  - Staff Meetings, Retreats, and In-Service, 2000-2005 (Box 19)
  - Strategic Planning, 1989-2005 (Box 19)
  - Website Design, 2003 (Box 19)
  - Other, 2001-2005 (Box 19)
- President's Files (Lana Pollack)
  The President's Files series documents the main activities and professional interests of MEC's executive officer. This series begins with the records of Lana Pollack and includes files devoted to MEC's major concerns during her tenure, writings, speeches, and files from her term as a fellow of the John F. Kennedy School of Government at Harvard University. Notable issues include environmental health, transportation, pollution prevention, clean energy development, and environmental toxins. Pollack's records also reflect MEC's interaction with the Michigan Department of Natural Resources, Department of Environmental Quality, the administrations of John Engler and Jennifer Granholm, and various pieces of legislation as the council sought to improve the state government's stewardship of the environment. The involvement of MEC (and Pollack, personally) in a variety of programs is well-documented in files related to the Environmental Communications and Community Organizing (ECCO) Initiative, the Michigan Economic and Environmental Roundtable (MEER), the Michigan Action Program (MAP), the Southeast Michigan Consortium for Water Quality, and the Michigan Land Use Leadership Council (MLULC). In addition, Pollack's records contain the results from numerous polls and focus groups commissioned by MEC.
  - ABB Union Background, 2001 (Box 19)
  - Adopt-A-Township Initiative, 1997-1999 (Box 19)
  - Ali (Muhammad) Event, 2002 (Box 19)
  - Alma Energy Park, 2006 (Box 19)
  - Bad News, 1996-1997 (Box 19)
  - BASF and Detroit River Pollution, 2002-2003 (Box 19)
  - Bazzani Architectural Firm (MEC Headquarters Building Project), 2005-2006 (Box 19)
    (includes architectural drawings)
  - Big Rock Point Power Plant, 2006 (Box 19)
  - Billboard Control, 2003 (Box 19)
  - Boat Pollution, 2002 (Box 19)
  - Bottle Bill, 1999-2006 (Box 19)
  - Bush, George W., 2001-2004 (Box 19)
  - Campaign Finance Reform (MI), 1998-1999 (Box 19)
  - Carbon Sequestration, 2007 (Box 19)
  - Cellular Communication Tower Placement, 2000 (Box 19)
  - Center for Automotive Research (CAR), 2003-2004 (Box 19)
  - Center for Michigan, 2007 (Box 19)
  - Center for Sustainable Systems, 2002 (Box 19)
  - Central Wayne Incinerator, 1995-1997 (Box 19)
  - Civil Society Institute, 2007 (Box 19)
  - Clean Air Act
    - Air Quality Issues, 1999-2005 (Box 19)
    - Anti-Smog Campaign, 1998 (Box 19)
    - Canada, 1994-1999 (Box 19)
    - Correspondence, 1995-1997 (Box 20)
    - Environmental Protection Agency, 1996-1997 (Box 20)
    - Ozone Transport, 1997-2000 (Box 20)
  - Clean Michigan Initiative, 1998-1999; 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Clean Up or Close Down Campaign, 1999 (Box 20)
  - Clinton River, 2000 (Box 20)
  - Concentrated Animal Feeding Operations (CAFOs), 1999-2002 (Box 20)
  - Conners Creek, 1998-2000; 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Conservancies, 2004 (Box 20)
  - Conservation News Service Summit, 1998-2006 (Box 20)
  - Contamination Site Clean-Up Funding, 1996 (Box 20)
  - Corporate Environmental Management Program (CEMP) at the University of Michigan, 2001-2002 (Box 20)
  - Daimler/Chrysler Magdeborg Forum, 2005 (Box 20)
  - David Dempsey
    - On the Brink: The Great Lakes in the 21st Century Publication Materials, 2004-2008 (Box 20)
    - Ruin and Recovery Publication Materials, 1999-2001 (Box 20)
    - William G. Milliken: Michigan's Passionate Moderate Publication Materials, 2003-2007 (Box 20)
  - Dereliction of Duty, 2004 (Box 20)
  - Detroit, 1995-1998 (Box 20)
  - Detroit Intermodal Freight Terminal, 2000-2001 (Box 20)
  - Detroit/Wayne County Port Authority, 2004-2007 (Box 20)
  - Detroiter's Working for Environmental Justice (DWEJ), 2001 (Box 20)
  - Dingell, John, 2002-2008; 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Dow Corporation, 2001-2006 (Box 20)
  - Earth Day, 2000-2004 (Box 20)
  - Economic Issues
    - Environmental Economics, 1998-2000 (Box 20)
    - Jobs, 2004 (Box 20)
    - Sustainable Businesses, 1996-2000 (Box 21)
    - Taxes, 1998-2004 (Box 21)
  - Electromagnetic Fields and Radiation, 1994 (Box 21)
  - Endangered Species, 1995 (Box 21)
  - Energy Issues
    - Alternative Energy Report, 2005-2006 (Box 21)
    - Clean Energy Technology (United Solar Ovonic Corporation), 2004-2005 (Box 21)
    - Coal (with MEC Report), 1999-2007 (Box 21)
    - Diesel, 2002-2005 (Box 21)
    - Energy Bills, 2005-2006 (Box 21)
    - Energy Code, 2005 (Box 21)
    - Energy Efficiency, 1999-2003 (Box 21)
    - Energy Independence, 2006 (Box 21)
    - Great Lakes Oil Drilling, 2000-2001 (Box 21)
    - Hydrogen, 2003 (Box 21)
    - Oil, 1999-2005 (Box 21)
    - Power Plants, 2003-2005 (Box 21)
    - Wind, 2001 (Box 21)
  - Engler, John, 1997-2002; 2 folders (Box 21)
  - Environmental Communications and Community Organizing (ECCO) Initiative, 2003-2005 (Box 21)
  - Environmental Defense Reports (DeCicco, John), 2003-2004 (Box 21)
  - Environmental Education, 1992-1997 (Box 21)
  - Environmental Grantmakers Association (EGA), 1997-1998 (Box 21)
  - Environmental Justice, 1994-1999; 2 folders (Box 21)
  - Environmental Mediation and Conflict Resolution, 2006 (Box 21)
  - Environmental Protection Agency Audit, 1996-2000; 2 folders (Box 21)
  - Federal Legislation and Legislative Agendas, 1996-2003 (Box 21)
  - "Filthy Five" Worst Polluters in Michigan, 1998 (Box 21)
  - Global Warming, 2000-2008; 2 folders (Box 21)
  - Graham, Christopher (MEC Member), 2005-2006 (Box 22)
  - Granholm, Jennifer
    - Attorney General, 1999-2000 (Box 22)
    - Governor, 2002-2007 (Box 22)
  - Grants
    - Energy Foundation, 2005-2006 (Box 22)
    - Ford Foundation, 1998-1999 (Box 22)
    - Frey Foundation, 1998 (Box 22)
    - Great Lakes Protection Fund, 1997-1998 (Box 22)
    - Madar Association Fund, 1997-1998 (Box 22)
  - Grayling, 2007 (Box 22)
  - Great Lakes Commission, 2000-2003 (Box 22)
  - Great Lakes Initiative, 1995-1997 (Box 22)
  - Great Lakes United, 1998 (Box 22)
  - "Greening the Governments" Report, 2002 (Box 22)
  - "Head in the Sand" Award, 1998 (Box 22)
  - Health Issues
    - Breast Cancer and the Environment Research Centers, 2003-2004; 2 folders (Box 22)
    - Cancer Rates (MI), 1998 (Box 22)
    - Children and Environmental Health, 1996-2000 (Box 22)
    - Doctors, 1997-1999 (Box 22)
    - Hospitals, 1997 (Box 22)
  - Herman, Susan (ME Consultant), 2005 (Box 22)
  - "History of Michigan Environmentalism", 2006 (Box 22)
  - Institute for Citizen Environmental Enforcement and Review (ICEER), 1997 (Box 22)
  - Immaculate Heart of Mary, 2003; 1 optical disks CD-ROMs (Box 22)
    includes CD-ROM about convent
  - International Initiatives, 2003 (Box 22)
  - Labor: United Auto Workers, 1997-2006 (Box 22)
  - Land Stewardship Initiative (LSI), 1996-2006 (Box 22)
  - League of Conservation Voters (LCV), 1998-2003 (Box 22)
  - Levin, Carl, 1997-2007; 2 folders (Box 22)
  - Litigation Services, 1999-2008 (Box 22)
  - Mackinac Center for Public Policy, 1995-2000 (Box 22)
  - Marathon Refinery Expansion, 2007 (Box 22)
  - Metropolitan Organizing Strategy Enabling Strength (MOSES), 1999-2001 (Box 22)
  - Michigan Action Program (MAP), 1997-1999; 2 folders (Box 23)
  - Michigan Association of Realtors, 1999-2001 (Box 23)
  - Michigan Coalition on the Environment and Jewish Life (MI-COEJL), 2003 (Box 23)
  - Michigan Department of Environmental Quality (DEQ)
    - MEC Report, 2002 (Box 23)
    - Chester, Steve, 2003-2004 (Box 23)
    - Harding, Russell, 1998-2000; 2 folders (Box 23)
    - General, 2004 (Box 23)
  - Michigan Department of Environmental Quality and Department of Natural Resources Funding, 2007 (Box 23)
  - Michigan Economic and Environmental Roundtable (MEER), 1996-2002 (Box 23)
  - Michigan Integrated Food and Farming Systems (MIFFS), 1995-1996 (Box 23)
  - Michigan Land Use Leadership Council (MLULC)
    - Reference Materials, 2003 (Box 23)
    - Administrative Materials, 2003 (Box 23)
    - General Meeting Materials, 2003-2004; 2 folders (Box 23)
    - Final Report, 2003 (Box 23)
  - Michigan Public Service Commission, 2006 (Box 23)
  - National Environmental Trust, 2007 (Box 23)
  - New Economy Initiative, 2008 (Box 23)
  - NAFTA, 1998-2003 (Box 23)
  - Pollack (Lana) Business Materials
    - Background, 1997-2002 (Box 23)
    - Blue Cross Blue Shield Speech and Supporting Materials, 1996-2000 (Box 23)
    - Correspondence, 1997-2006 (Box 23)
    - Speeches, 1995-2006; 2 folders (Box 24)
    - Writings
      - Detroit News, 1997-2004 (Box 24)
      - General, 1997-2003; 1 floppy disks 3.5" (Box 24)
        (includes MS Word documents on 4 3.5 in. floppy disks)
  - Polls and Focus Groups, 1995-2003 (Box 24)
  - Polluter Pay Legislation, 1990-1995 (Box 24)
  - Pollution Prevention, 1997-1998 (Box 24)
  - Progressive Summit, undated (Box 24)
  - Radio Appearances, 1997-2008 (Box 24)
  - ReCellular Inc., 2008 (Box 24)
  - Risk Assessment and Environmental Regulations, 1995 (Box 24)
  - Sand Dunes, 1999-2001 (Box 24)
  - Save Our Land Save Our Future, 1998 (Box 24)
  - Science Advisory Committee, 2000-2002 (Box 24)
  - Science Seminars, 1999-2001 (Box 24)
  - Southeast Michigan Consortium for Water Quality, 2001-2006; 3 folders (Box 24)
  - State Environmental Leadership Program (SELP), 1998-2005 (Box 24)
  - Takings, 1995 (Box 24)
  - Tondu Power Plant Proposal, 2003-2004 (Box 24)
  - Toxins
    - Endocrine Disrupters, 1994-1998; 3 folders (Box 25)
    - Fish Consumption Advisories, 1996-1997 (Box 25)
    - Lead, 1995-2003 (Box 25)
    - Mercury, 1998-2006 (Box 25)
    - Pesticides, 1998-2006 (Box 25)
    - Regulations, 1997-2002 (Box 25)
  - Transportation Issues
    - "Advocating Comprehensive Transit in Southeast Michigan" (Report), 2007 (Box 25)
    - Clean Car Campaign, 1997-2006 (Box 25)
    - Clean Car Round-Up, 2002-2003 (Box 25)
    - Fuel Efficiency Tax Credits, 1999 (Box 25)
    - High Speed Rail, 1997 (Box 25)
    - Hybrids and Advanced Diesels (HADS), 2003-2005 (Box 25)
    - "Remote Sensing Applications for Air Quality Issues in Transportation" (Report), 1999 (Box 25)
  - University of Michigan, 1996-2001 (Box 25)
  - Waste Management, 2000 (Box 25)
  - Water
    - Great Lakes Contamination, 2000-2005 (Box 25)
    - Legislation, 2008 (Box 25)
    - General, 2002-2005 (Box 25)
  - Wetlands, 1990-1998 (Box 25)
  - "Where Do the Children Play" Documentary Materials, 2002-2003 (Box 25)
  - Wolverine Power and Mid-Michigan Energy, 2008 (Box 25)
- Associate Director's Files (Patrick Diehl)
  The Associate Director's Files series contains materials related to the MEC administrator whose main responsibility is fund raising and grant management (a role subsequently filled by the Finance and Development Director). Patrick Diehl was MEC's first Associate Director and served in this capacity from 1996 to 2006. While his records deal with a variety of administrative functions, they consist mainly of information related to MEC grants and granting agencies (such as the Americans, Frey, and Mott Foundations) and related correspondence, reports, and budgets. This series also reflects Diehl's earlier work with Clean Water Action, his service on the board of the Environmental Fund for Michigan, and his work with the Michigan Great Printer's Project.
  - Administrative Records
    - Financial Information, 1996 (Box 25)
    - Fundraising, 1996-1997 (Box 25)
    - Grant Deliverables, 2002-2004 (Box 25)
    - Legislative Agenda, 1997 (Box 25)
    - Meeting Materials, 1996-2005 (Box 25)
      (includes Power Point presentation on CD)
    - Member Agreements, 1999-2005 (Box 25)
    - Official Policies, 1996 (Box 25)
    - Position Announcements, 1996 (Box 25)
    - Reorganization Proposal, 2004 (Box 25)
    - "Strange Bedfellows": MEC Partners, 2005 (Box 25)
  - Brater Environmental Legislation, 1997 (Box 26)
  - Clean Water Action, 1992-1993 (Box 26)
  - Coastal Community Land Use Outreach Program, 2005-2006 (Box 26)
  - Crystal River, 1995 (Box 26)
  - Dell Computer Program, 2003 (Box 26)
  - Department of Environmental Quality Creation, 1995 (Box 26)
  - Diehl (Patrick) Business Materials
    - Correspondence (Box 26)
    - Writings (Box 26)
  - Drain Code Revision, 1995 (Box 26)
  - Environmental Fund for Michigan
    - Board Manual with Supporting Materials, 1996-1999 (Box 26)
      (originally in a binder)
    - Meeting Agendas and Minutes, 1996-1997 (Box 26)
  - Farmland Protection, 1998-2002 (Box 26)
  - Farmland Protection Handbook and Associated Materials, 1997-1998 (Box 26)
  - Fish Advisories, 1997 (Box 26)
  - Garmon (Brad) Projects, 2004 (Box 26)
  - Garrity, Jeff (Freelance Writer), 1998 (Box 26)
  - Grants
    - Americana Foundation, 1999-2005; 2 folders (Box 26)
    - Atticus Trust, 2001-2002 (Box 26)
    - Austin Memorial Foundation, 2001 (Box 26)
    - Bauman Foundation, 1998-2004 (Box 26)
    - Beldon Fund, 2000-2005 (Box 26)
    - Belvedere Fund, 2001 (Box 26)
    - Clear the Air, 2000-2001 (Box 26)
    - Energy Foundation, 1998 (Box 26)
    - Florence Fund, 1999 (Box 26)
    - Ford Motor Company Fund, 2000-2004 (Box 26)
    - Frey Foundation, 1995-2005; 2 folders (Box 26)
    - Herman Miller Company, Inc., 1999 (Box 26)
    - Hewlett Foundation, 2002 (Box 26)
    - J.C. Downing Foundation, 1999 (Box 26)
    - Joyce Foundation, 1997-1998; 2004 (Box 26)
    - Kellogg Foundation, 1996-1997 (Box 26)
    - Livingston Foundation, 1998 (Box 26)
    - Michigan Great Lakes Protection Fund, 1996-1998 (Box 26)
    - Mott Foundation, 1999-2004; 2 folders (Box 27)
    - National Environmental Trust, 2001-2004 (Box 27)
    - North American Fund for Environmental Cooperation, 1996-1998 (Box 27)
    - Proteus Fund, 2004-2005 (Box 27)
    - State Environmental Leadership Program (SELP), 2002-2003 (Box 27)
    - Towlsey Foundation, 1997-2000 (Box 27)
    - Other, 1997-2005 (Box 27)
  - Harbut, Dr. Michael, 1997 (Box 27)
  - Lake Michigan Federation Agreement, 2002 (Box 27)
  - Land Stewardship Conference, 1995 (Box 27)
  - Landon Companies' Supplemental Environmental Project Agreement, 2003 (Box 27)
  - League of Conservation Voters' Environmental Scorecard, 1998 (Box 27)
  - Leelanau Agriculture Alliance "Land Conservation Toolkit", 1998 (Box 27)
  - Michigan Great Printers Project (GPP)
    - Financial Information, 1996-1997 (Box 27)
    - Grant Materials, 1997 (Box 27)
    - McNaughton and Gunn, Inc. Press Event, 1996 (Box 27)
      (includes photo)
    - Meetings and Memoranda, 1996 (Box 27)
    - Reports, 1996-1999 (Box 27)
  - Michigan Integrated Food and Farming Systems (MIFFS), 1997 (Box 27)
  - Political Effectiveness Project (Institute for Conservation Leadership), 1996-1997 (Box 27)
  - Pollution Prevention, 1996 (Box 27)
  - Sprawl Action Resource Centers (SpARCs), 2004 (Box 27)
  - Stroh, Peter, 2002 (Box 27)
  - Subdivision Control Act, 1997 (Box 27)
  - Transportation Spending and Land Use, 1999-2003 (Box 27)
- Policy Advisor's Files (David Dempsey)
  The Policy Advisor's Files series includes a large body of information used by MEC to establish and support its position on a variety of environmental issues. David Dempsey served as MEC Interim Executive Director from 1982-1983 but left the council to serve Governor Jim Blanchard; he returned in 1994 and served as Senior Policy Advisor until his departure in 2004 (after which he worked as a consultant). Dempsey's files include background information and drafts for MEC publications and position papers dealing with such topics as Great Lakes pollution, environmentally friendly governance, environmental health, and pollution prevention. This series also contains material related to Dempsey's time with Clean Water Action, his personal work on Michigan's environmental history, and the organizational records of the west Michigan group Hope for the Dunes.
  - Children's Health, 1997-2000 (Box 27)
  - Clean Corporate Citizen Program, 1997 (Box 27)
  - Clean Michigan Initiative Work Group, 1998 (Box 27)
  - Clean Water Action, 1990-1993 (Box 27)
  - "Conservation/Environmental Historical Markers", undated (Box 27)
  - Critical Materials Register and Annual Wastewater Reporting Program, 1993-1999 (Box 27)
  - Cross Village Boat Ramp, 1994 (Box 27)
  - Crotty Street Channel Remedial Action Plan, 1999 (Box 27)
  - Dempsey (David) Business Records
    - Correspondence, 1996-2004 (Box 27)
    - "Dereliction of Duty" (Report on DEQ), 2000 (Box 27)
    - On the Brink: The Great Lakes in the 21st Century (Publication Materials), 2004 (Box 27)
    - "Restoring Greatness to Government: Protecting the Great Lakes in the 21st Century" (Report and Supporting Materials), 2001-2003 (Box 27)
    - "A Spreading Stain: Michigan's Groundwater Dead Zones" (Report with Research Materials), 2000 (Box 27)
    - Writings (Various), 2004 (Box 27)
  - Drinking Water Safety, 1998 (Box 28)
  - Dwarf Lake Iris Protection, 1997-1998 (Box 28)
  - Environmental Communications and Community Organizing (ECCO) Initiative, 2001 (Box 28)
  - Environmental Disposal Systems, Inc. Hazardous Waste Facility, 1998-2001; 2 folders (Box 28)
  - Environmental Investigations Unit (DNR/DEQ), 1977; 1992-1999 (Box 28)
  - Environmental Justice, 1992-1995 (Box 28)
  - Grading the Governments Project
    - Project Advisors and Meeting Information, 2001 (Box 28)
    - "Greening the Governments" Report, 2001-2002 (Box 28)
  - Grant Reports, 1995-2000 (Box 28)
  - "Great Lakes Leaks" (MEC Report), 2002-2003 (Box 28)
  - Great Lakes Policy Issues, 2000-2004 (Box 28)
  - Great Lakes Water Quality Agreement Report, 2000 (Box 28)
  - Hooker Chemical (Contamination in White Lake, MI), 1968-2000 (Box 28)
  - Humbug Marsh, 1998-1999 (Box 28)
  - "The Impacts of Lead in Michigan" (Michigan Environmental Science Board Report), 1995 (Box 28)
  - Ingham County Groundwater Commission, 1995 (Box 28)
  - Inland Lake Protection, 1995-1997 (Box 28)
  - Kalamazoo River Superfund Site, 1997-2000 (Box 28)
  - Lake Erie Ecosystem Organizing Project, 2004 (Box 28)
  - Land Use Clearinghouse Index, undated (Box 28)
  - Lead Poisoning Prevention, 1999 (Box 28)
  - Lindane Ban, 2004 (Box 28)
  - Michigan Democratic Party Environmental Caucus, 2002 (Box 28)
  - Michigan Lead Safe Partnership Report, 2004 (Box 28)
  - Michigan Legislation
    - HB 4342 (DEQ Permit Review Board), 1997 (Box 28)
    - Polluter Pay Bills and Amendments, 1995-1999 (Box 28)
    - SB 112 (Subdivision Control Act), 1996-1997 (Box 28)
  - Motor Wheel Disposal Site, 1994-2002; 3 folders (Box 28)
  - Old Growth Designation in Luce County, 2003-2004 (Box 28)
    (includes photos)
  - Photographs and Slides, 1930s-2004 (Box 28)
  - "Policies that Promote Urban Sprawl" (Report), undated (Box 29)
  - Pollution Incident Prevention Plans, 1997-2000 (Box 29)
  - Pollution Prevention, 1993-1994 (Box 29)
  - Presque Isle Power Plant, 1998 (Box 29)